Today, I'm going to talk to you about sketching electronics.
اليوم سأحدثكم عن رسم الإلكترونيات
I'm, among several other things, an electrical engineer,
وأنا، من بين عدة أمور أخرى، مهندسة كهربائية،
and that means that I spend a good amount of time
وهذا يعني أنني أقضي مدة لا بأس بها
designing and building new pieces of technology,
في تصميم وصناعة قطع جديدة من التكنولوجيا،
and more specifically designing and building electronics.
وأكثر تحديداً تصميم وبناء الإلكترونيات.
And what I've found is that the process of designing
وما وجدته هو أن عملية تصميم
and building electronics is problematic in all sorts of ways.
وبناء الإلكترونيات إشكالية بشتى أنواع الطرق.
So it's a really slow process, it's really expensive,
إذا هي عملية بطيئة جداّ ومكلفة جداّ،
and the outcome of that process,
ونتيجة تلك العملية،
namely electronic circuit boards,
أساسا، لوحات دوائر إلكترونية،
are limited in all sorts of kind of interesting ways.
هي محدودة في جميع الطرق المثيرة للاهتمام.
So they're really small, generally, they're square
إنها صغيرة جداً على العموم، وهي مربعة
and flat and hard, and frankly, most of them
ومسطحة وقاسية وبصراحة فمعظمها
just aren't very attractive, and so my team and I
ليست جذّابة ، ولذلك أنا وفريقي
have been thinking of ways to really change and mix up
كنا نفكر في طرق لتغيير وخلط
the process and the outcome of designing electronics.
العملية ونتائج تصميم الإلكترونيات
And so what if you could design and build electronics
فكيف لو كان بإمكانك تصميم وبناء الإلكترونيات
like this? So what if you could do it extremely quickly,
هكذا؟ إذاً ماذا لو أمكنك أن تفعل ذلك بسرعة بالغة،
extremely inexpensively, and maybe more interestingly,
وتكلفة زهيدة جداً، وربما بشكل أكثر إثارة للاهتمام،
really fluidly and expressively and even improvisationally?
بسلاسة وطريقة معبرة وحتى بطريقة ارتجالية؟
Wouldn't that be so cool, and that wouldn't that open up
ألن يكون ذلك رائعاً جداً، ذلك سيفتح
all sorts of new possibilities?
إمكانيات جديدة عديدة؟
I'm going to share with you two projects that are
سأطلعكم على اثنين من المشاريع والتي هي
investigations along these lines, and we'll start with this one.
تحقيقات في هذا الاتجاه، وسوف نبدأ بهذه.
(Video) Magnetic electronic pieces and ferrous paper.
(فيديو) قطع إلكترونية مغناطيسية وورقة حديدية.
A conductive pen from the Lewis lab at UIUC.
قلم موصل من مختبر لويس في جامعة إلينوي.
Sticker templates.
قوالب لصق.
Speed x 4.
سرعة x 4.
Making a switch.
صنع مفتاح
Music: DJ Shadow.
الموسيقى: ظل الدي جي.
Adding some intelligence with a microcontroller.
إضافة بعض الذكاء بمتحكم دقيق.
Sketching an interface.
رسم واجهة.
(Music)
(موسيقى)
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Pretty cool, huh? We think so.
رائع، أليس كذلك؟ نحن نعتقد ذلك.
So now that we developed these tools
إذاً الآن بعد أن قمنا بتطوير هذه الأدوات
and found these materials that let us do these things,
ووجدنا هذه المواد التي تتيح لنا القيام بهذه الأمور،
we started to realize that, essentially, anything
بدأنا ندرك أنه، أساسا، أي شيء
that we can do with paper, anything that we can do
يمكن أن نفعله مع الورق، أي شيء يمكن أن نفعله
with a piece of paper and a pen
مع قطعة من الورق وقلم
we can now do with electronics.
يمكن أن نفعله الآن مع الإلكترونيات.
So the next project that I want to show you is kind of a
المشروع القادم الذي أريد أن أريكم إياه هو نوع من
deeper exploration of that possibility.
استكشاف أعمق لتلك الإمكانية.
And I'll kind of let it speak for itself.
وسأسمح لها أن تتحدث عن نفسها.
(Music)
(موسيقى)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
So the next step for us in this process
لذلك الخطوة التالية بالنسبة لنا في هذه العملية
is now to find a way to let all of you
هو إيجاد وسيلة للسماح لكم جميعا الآن
build things like this,
ببناء أشياء مثل هذه،
and so the way that we're approaching that is by
وبالتالي فإن المقاربة التي نعتمدها هي من خلال
teaching workshops to people where we explain
تقديم ورشات عمل للناس حيث نشرح
how they can use these kinds of tools, and then also
كيف يمكنهم استخدام هذه الأنواع من أدوات، ثم أيضا
working to get the tools and the materials and techniques
نعمل على الحصول على الأدوات والمواد والتقنيات
out into the real world in a variety of ways.
واخراجها إلى العالم الحقيقي في مجموعة متنوعة من الطرق.
And so sometime soon, you'll be able to play and build
وبالتالي في وقت قريب، ستكون قادراً على اللعب والبناء
and sketch with electronics in this fundamentally new way.
والرسم بالإلكترونيات بهذه الطريقة الجديدة السهلة.
So thank you very much. (Applause)
لذا شكرا جزيلا لكم.(تصفيق)